

Paulo Silva Front-end Developer

Q Dublin, Ireland

Profile

I am a Front-end Developer with a background in 3D and interactive media.

I have been programming since I was quite young. I started by programming games with BASIC for my TI-83 plus calculator. Over the years I have been expanding my knowledge in software engineering and design.

I have created games for mobile and pc, worked on Computer Visualization and 3d Computer Graphics.

Lately I have focused on web development. Each day the web is more

present in our lives. With new technologies that allow for ever more dynamic websites, the possibilities for innovation are almost endless!

I want to use technology to make life simpler and more enjoyable.

I have experience developing modern, great looking websites that are fully responsive and mobile friendly.

Details

■ paulo.silva.webdev@gmail.com

www.paulosilva.me

O github.com/paulocoding

□ 0874618672

Programming languages

Javascript, html, css, sass, C, C#, PHP, SQL, Ruby.

Tools / Frameworks

gulp, jQuery, AngularJS, Bootstrap.

Software

git, Atom, Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio 2010-2015, Chrome Dev Tools.

Photoshop CS-CS6 Unity 3D, Maya, 3ds Max, Blender.

Operative Systems

Linux (Ubuntu), Windows 98-10.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer | Freelance

April- June 2016

Developing websites that are responsive and mobile friendly.

Technologies - HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Angular.

Lighting Technical Director and Compositor | Boulder Media

January - May 2015

Worked on several TV projects for Disney XD and BBC.

Developed tools to maintain consistency and automated repetitive tasks.

Compositing for a 2D show and lighting and rendering for a 3D show.

Technologies: AfterFx, 3ds Max, javascript, maxscript.

Lighting Technical Director | EGG Post Production

August 2014 - November 2014

I worked on the lighting team of the feature film Ghost Hunters: On Icy Trails.

Responsible for lighting and rendering the 3D elements of the show.

Matching the lighting with the live action footage and solve any technical problems.

Modeler, Lighting TD, Compositor | Illusive Studios

October 2013 - January 2014

Worked on several tv commercials.

The tasks involved modeling and setting up assets for rendering.

Lighting, Rendering and Compositing.

3D Generalist | Freelance

January 2012 - October 2013

3D assets for an adventure game prototype codename "Bricks" using unity 3D.

Elements for an interactive 3D architecture project using Unity 3D.

City modeling based on reference maps for a realtime application.

Game Developer | Flying Turtle Software

January 2010 - October 2013

Co-Founder of Flying Turtle Software.

Managed task assignment, priorities and issues using Redmine.

Game Director for the game "A Walk in the dark", published on Steam

Game Designer and content creator for the mobile game Samarium Wars.

3D Generalist | ZPX - Zona Paradoxal

July 2009 - August 2011

3D medical applications using Unity 3D.

UI design. Serious Games. Visualization.

IOS games and Apps.

3D Animator | PMV design

2008 - 2009

Worked as an Animator on the 3D tv show "Gomby".

Education

Multimedia Design | University of Beira Interior

Bachelor 2005-2008

Web Development. Graphic Design. Usability and User Experience.

Photography, Video and Audio creation and editing. 3D Animation.

Software Engineering | University of Minho

Bachelor (unfinished) 2003-2005

Programming paradigms. Object Oriented programming.

Algorithms and Data Structures. Computer Architecture.

Programming in C, Java, haskell, prolog.

Information Technology | Alcanena Secondary School

Secondary Education 2000-2003

Introduction to programming concepts.

Programming in Pascal, C, Visual Basic and SQL.

Additional Education

Responsive Web Design Fundamentals | Udacity

February - March 2016

Course run by GDG Dublin Meetup

Web Developer Bootcamp with Rails | CodeManual

November 2015 - January 2016

Course run by https://codermanual.com/

JavaScript Language | CodeSchool

October 2015

Course run by www.codeschool.com

HTML/CSS Path | CodeSchool

September 2015

Course run by www.codeschool.com

CS50x Introduction to Computer Science | edX - HarvardX

June - September 2015

Course run by www.edx.org

Projects

Anabela's website

April 2016

www.anabelafaria.com

Technologies: html, css, bootstrap, javascript, jquery

Snake Game in html5

January 2016

http://www.paulosilva.me/projects/snake/snake.html

Technologies: html, css, javascript, jquery

Presentations

Javascript Objects presentation | Web Developers Ireland Meetup

May 2016

http://www.paulosilva.me/projects/objects-js/

Gulp presentation | Web Developers Ireland Meetup

January 2016

http://www.paulosilva.me/projects/gulp-p/

Miscellaneous

I do photography as a hobby, like to play board games with friends and go for a long walk with my camera on hand, particularly in natural environments. I enjoy cooking and eating good food.

I am able to work in Ireland with no need for a visa (EU Citizen).